<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Essays on Ramtin Babaei</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Essays on Ramtin Babaei</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/essays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Driven by Obsession</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/driven-by-obsession/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/driven-by-obsession/</guid>
      <description>Some people are motivated. But Motivation comes and goes, it‘s main nature is equal to inconsistency. Now as hunters and gatherers, our motivation was extremely high to get food, otherwise we would die. And when the hunters and gatherers didn’t have motivation, they needed the discipline to do their job and get to the goal. It was crucial, it was about life and death.&#xA;Today, the basics of survival are readily available for many: food from the supermarket and a place to sleep.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some people are motivated. But Motivation comes and goes, it‘s main nature is equal to inconsistency. Now as hunters and gatherers, our motivation was extremely high to get food, otherwise we would die. And when the hunters and gatherers didn’t have motivation, they needed the discipline to do their job and get to the goal. It was crucial, it was about life and death.</p>
<p>Today, the basics of survival are readily available for many: food from the supermarket and a place to sleep. Yet, to achieve these comforts, work is still required, albeit in a different form. To truly enrich our lives, discipline becomes essential. Whether the goal is to get in shape, secure a higher-paying job, or write a book, consistency is key. Without it, the desired outcomes remain out of reach.</p>
<p>But what does it take to ascend to the ranks of the truly exceptional, like Leonardo da Vinci, Marie Curie, Steve Jobs, Elon Musk, or Muhammad Ali? What elevates them to such heights? The answer is singular: obsession. This isn&rsquo;t limited to the icons of history or industry. Consider those who push the boundaries in ultramarathons or other extreme endeavors; mere motivation won&rsquo;t carry them far. They require discipline. Yet, even discipline might falter in providing the necessary drive. What truly propels them is obsession — obsession with the process, the goal, or the craft itself. Without this intense focus, the challenges and pain become overwhelming. Figures like Elon Musk, who operate in an &ldquo;extreme hardcore mode,&rdquo; are driven by an obsession, whether it&rsquo;s colonizing Mars, achieving victory, or mastering their art.</p>
<p>Obsession can indeed propel you to greatness, but it comes with a shadow side that might undo you. To be obsessed is to commit fully, to live in a constant state of &lsquo;hardcore mode,&rsquo; where thoughts revolve incessantly around one singular focus. Over time, this intensity often leads to isolation. You might find yourself alone, or surrounded only by those who match your fervor — individuals who together can achieve extraordinary feats. However, this path often results in the loss of friendships, strained relationships, or even one&rsquo;s health, both mental and physical. This isn&rsquo;t to say that those who are obsessively driven can&rsquo;t lead happy lives; rather, it requires another form of obsession: the obsession with balance.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
